hey what's up everybody in this video I want
to talk about picking the best most marketable
topics for your coaching or online course business
for those you I haven't met yet my name is jerem
Kowski and I've been in the online course and
coaching space for almost 22 years I've been
building these businesses back when we did CD
and DVD products I built multiple businesses
in the space over $20 million and what I focus
on now is every single day every single week is
helping beginners go from zero virtually no idea
no following nobody knowing who they are to be
able to build a multi6 and even seven figureure
business and that's what I walk you through and
that's what I show you how to do and that's what
this YouTube channel is for that's what my podcast
is for that's what my coaching program the client
growth accelerator is for I'd love to work with
you and continue to help you to be able to do
that this is exactly what I help people do is
I come alongside them on the nuances of what it
takes to actually make this thing work truth is
there's not a lot of coaches or mentors that are
out there that actually have the experience that
I have and the results and the track record to
be able to do this with beginners and so that's
what I love to do and that's what today's
lesson is all about is if you're somebody
who's like listen I want to get into the coaching
online course space how do I know what the best
topics to use are I actually have a brand new
free class right now over my website all about
starting your own sixf figureure online course
or coaching business you should go check that out
there also be a link in the description below if
that's a current active class that we're hosting
right now at the time of this recording now what
I want to show you is a few cheat codes that you
can use to be able to accelerate your journey
to know what is marketable what is profitable
and I also want to give you and dive into
something that's a little bit more advanced
but that's going to save you up to 2 to 3 years of
time time that I see all the time with my clients
people that I work with that they tell me after
a couple of years wow I finally got it and they
made a decision that if they had only decided
this sooner it actually would have saved them
a lot of time a lot of effort a lot of money
to be able to accomplish their goals okay and
so the number one thing is this is yes of course
you need to have something that's marketable you
need to have something that is profitable people
are going to pay you for information but not just
information but also the transformation that that
information provides when somebody buys a course
from you they're not just paying for information
they're paying for access to you they're paying
for being able to get what like to pick your
brain sort of virtually and be able to get what
you can provide them as a result and an outcome
to actually make the kind of money that you want
to make and what is marketable you got to look at
the result the end outcome and the transformation
that you're going to deliver and then we work
backwards from there we got to figure out what
is the desire of the person that we are marketing
to and So based on their desires that's how we're
going to know exactly what they want to buy
from us is what do they desire the most what
do they they they long for what do they really
really want truth is this there's a lot of Great
Courses trainers mentors information you can
find on YouTube and all that but what actually
is profitable is figuring out okay what is the
desire that is just enough enough of a difficulty
that somebody needs to make an investment because
they've been trying to figure it out by watching
videos they've been trying to figure it out on
social media they've been trying to figure out on
their own and they just can't put the final pieces
together and what you end up doing is you end up
kind of bringing all those pieces together in one
place and providing that result for them you know
I mean a lot of people they tell me Jeremiah
I've listened to the trainings I've listen
to the courses I've gone through tons of coaching
programs and I still can't seem to make money with
my course I still can't seem to get people to buy
my program and they come into the client growth
accelerator that I have where we have a system
that creates consistent profit consistent income
direct Clarity on your messaging and massive
impact on people's lives that you're reaching
and when all of those things come together it
creates Financial Freedom and time freedom for
our clients where they are able to get massive
results kind like my client Sean deep he was able
to make $112,000 on a test run being able to do
this we tweaked just a few little things and he
tested it out and made $112,000 like Kim she made
over $30,000 in a down Market in real estate being
able to do this by launching an offer to people on
how to flip houses in a market where real estate
really wasn't thriving but she was able to use the
strategies of what do people want what is their
desire to be able to do this now there's a couple
of ways of figuring out what are those topics that
they have if you have no idea what topic to go off
of there's a couple of really fun things that you
can do that I'm going to show you here in a second
but if you do have an idea here's what I recommend
that people do okay I'm going to show you if you
have no clue you have no idea in just a second but
if you do have a couple of ideas here's what
I recommend is write them down on a piece of
paper write down some of the ideas that you have
for a course or coaching program and then what we
can do is we can bring those into something like
chat GPT to be able to say okay how does this all
tie together to be able to create our own program
so let's say I want to create a fitness program
for women let me move my my little video window
here not sure why over there um with a retreat
and it focuses on Mental Health but also uh diet
and exercise and I want it to be for women over 45
okay generate me 20 ideas for a title for a course
on this okay and this is where chat GPT is really
cool because it can give you ideas on how to bring
and marry all of those different things together
and so one of the things that I encourage people
to do and by the way you can notice I have a
little typo there AI is really cool because it'll
ignore your typos and it knows exactly what you're
actually wanting to say so what ends up happening
is is that if you can write down some of the ideas
that you already have right now for how you want
to start who you want to help we can merge those
together into a program that provides a complete
transformation for people to be able to do this
now if you don't have any idea of where to start
here's what I like to do is I like to go into chat
gbt and I like to say this okay um I I want to
sell a course online but I have no idea where to
start ask me a series of questions to see what
strengths I have that are marketable to teach
a course on okay and so what's cool is it's going
to be able to ask questions right here what skills
or topics do you feel deeply confidently about
that you could teach about what challenges have
you overcome what passions and interests common
questions from others what's your target audience
who do you want to work with beginners Advanced
professionals specific age group your unique
approach results and outcomes and what's really
cool is overall when you can kind of put some of
this together it will help you the AI can actually
help you come up with those ideas of what to do
of what to talk about now let's say that we have
no idea of what to do generate me a list of 100
very different niches in a variety of Industries
and and uh professions for a coaching or online
course business okay and what's cool is the AI
is able to go to work and actually give us a 100
different niches in different industries that you
could create a coaching program around and these
are really specific and so this gives you ideas
as far as different things that you could Mentor
people on or that you could create courses on or
stuff like that now to make it marketable you got
to figure out okay what is the actual end outcome
that these people want so for instance mindful
parenting for teens this is one right here how
can we make mindful parenting for teens more
marketable online now I want to pause right here
you might be saying Jeremiah I don't really want
to use AI I I want to know what these ideas are
myself I want to be original all this can I tell
you this is that the AI is a great way to get
your mind coming up with ideas it's a great way
to unlock your own thinking and unlock your own
mind so that you're not struggling to wonder will
this work is is this something that I want to do
and that you can get clarity on things without
having to take a ton of effort a ton of time to
be able to do it one of the mistakes I see a lot
of people make is that they feel like oh I need
to come up with this idea from just my mind with
no assistance from a coach with no assistance from
artificial intelligence and that for some reason
that that validates me and makes me more worth
it and it's more original because of that can I
tell you this that's that's a lie it's a facade
that's not really a healthy way of thinking but
I meet a a lot of coaches and mentors that they
think that way and it's preventing them it keeps
them thinking small it keeps them living small
and it keeps them from actually reaching their
goals and so I want to challenge you that if
that's you if you're like I just don't want
to use AI tools or anything like this to be able
to come up with ideas I would challenge the fact
that unfortunately in this industry fortunately
or unfortunately or not that in this industry
everybody is using artificial intelligence and you
cannot compete anymore if you're not using this to
come up with different ideas of what you want to
work with Okay so this gives us some ideas right
here of how to make this original this gives us
some ideas of how to turn this into something that
is unique and original right here what are some
things specifically that you can offer you can
offer a mindful parenting road map 10 exercises
to connect with your teens you can leverage
storytelling and now here's the thing is that
when you're creating your own course or coaching
program you want it to be attached to stuff that
you've actually done you wanted to be tied to
stuff that you have actually accomplished that
you have experienced in because here's why when
you can pull from your experience and your stories
you might say well why would anybody want to hear
those things because the person who is struggling
with the thing that is a few steps behind you that
you can pull up to your level by them hearing the
stories of what you struggled with what you went
through what you learned what you accomplished you
provide them the faith and the belief that they
can do it themselves and so we don't need need to
be like this amazing orator great teacher Ted Talk
level speaker to be able to be successful we just
need to learn how to connect with people you just
need to learn how to communicate with the right
people at the right time that are where you were
that are maybe where clients of yours were people
that you can help and then what you're able to do
is you're able to pull them up to that level
and what's great is it provides authenticity
it allows you to connect with people in
an authentic way and isn't that way better
is connecting with people in a much more authentic
way instead of trying to be fake or perfect or all
those things like that I I'm telling you this the
people that that succeed in this industry they
get it and they understand this thing more than
anything else is that perfectionism is the enemy
of your success needing to be perfect the fear of
what other people think about you the worry about
looking perfect sounding perfect doing all the
perfect things ACC and packaging it so perfectly
that is not going to make you any kind of money
but it's a about learning who are you helping
what are their desires and how can you take those
desires to produce a result in somebody I want to
take this idea of mindful of parenting for teens
generate for me 20 desires that I could attach a
marketing offer to for this course okay what are
20 desires that they have they want to reconnect
with their team they want to reduce household
tension they they want to help manage stress
they want to stop arguing and start communicating
so you can see for any Niche for any industry you
can dive into what are those desires and I think
that like just by taking these top five that it
generates right here create me 20 ideas for a
course that combines these top five and really
is focused on an end result outcome generated
in the title okay reconnect and Thrive Harmony
at home stressfree teen stress free family tools
to claim to calm communicate and connect I like
this one right here okay generate me a sales
letter to promote this program in a persuasive
conversational and informal tone okay okay
discover the secrets of raising confident
happy teens without drama introducing stress-free
teens stress-free family are you finding yourself
stuck in the same cycle with your teen one minute
things are fine the next and innocent conversation
turns into an argument suddenly the whole house
feels tense and now right now what we've done
is we've literally taken that one idea that just
that one idea of mindful parenting for teens and
now we have something tangible that you could
build a program around right here and you could
literally run through you watch back through this
video use the same prompting that I used and type
in some of these ideas for your own Niche for
your own business and you will be amazed what
chat GPT provides what it comes out with for this
and then we can start to Market it and then we can
start to reach people when you connect around the
desires that people have and you say okay how can
I go find those people that are online because
the truth is what makes makes it marketable is
that there are people that are looking for the
desired outcome that you help deliver they're
searching for it they're actively looking for it
and so when they see an Instagram reel or they see
an advertisement or they see a YouTube video or
they're on your email list and you send them an
email around the the topic that you help people
with it's an instant sale they instantly want to
become your client they instantly want to work
with you through this because you have connected
directly with right where people are at with right
with what they need and you're able to pull them
from where they are to create a transformation in
their life and people will make an investment in
that with you people will invest their finances
with you to be able to do that for them they want
to fly and go beyond where they are at right now
to go to the next level and that's what your job
is when you're making a course when you're making
a coaching program your goal is to help raise
people up to the next level with you to go higher
than where they are at right now to be able to
achieve something that they've only ever dreamed
of and so when we can figure out what are those
desires that people have and for any Niche I'll
tell you the AI is brilliant at figuring out those
desires because it understands the psychology
it understands that even better we could even
dive into it deeper like this act as an expert in
the topic above and generate a list for me of 10
of the top deeper desires results Transformations
and outcomes that the person above would want and
the problems stopping them from getting there that
they wouldn't normally tell other people and this
right here really is one of the biggest things
that's going to help you be able to accomplish
your goals in your business I'm I'm looking for a
book here that's on my shelf um you know I don't
see it which is interesting oh it's right here The
Ultimate Sales letter so this book right here The
Ultimate Sales letter by Dan Kennedy talks all
about this it talks about by getting into the
mind of your Target customer the 10 smart Market
diagnosis questions what keeps them awake at night
what are they afraid of what are they angry
about and so what we could even do is we could
ask the AI take take Dan Kennedy's 10 smart Market
diagnosis questions from the ultimate salesletter
book and generate them for the above okay and so
it's literally going to take these 10 smart Market
diagnosis questions right here what are they
afraid of they have a fear that their teen will
fall into harmful Behavior what are they angry
about what keeps them up at night what are their
top three frustrations what trends are occurring
in their lives what do they secretly desire the
most at the at the heart of it is genuine trusting
relationship with a team what's their built-in
bias do they have their own language communication
tools who else is selling something similar who
else has tried and failed and now what we can do
is take all of the above and generate me a new
sales letter for this program that is dialed in
better around what will persuade someone finally
a proven way to raise confident happy teens with
all this without all the stress arguments and emo
distance do ever feel like your relationship is
slipping through your fingers one minute you're
opening up the next they're shutting down rolling
their eyes and retreating into silence and check
this out that has that dialed in so much better
even around exactly what these parents want if
you're a parent who feels helpless trying to
get through to your teen wants to create a a
calm environment tired of the constant arguing
in silence dreams of raising confident resilient
teens here's what they might not tell anyone
and why we get it we understand the fear ear
that go unspoken this is amazing right here okay
now generate me 20 new titles for this coaching
program based on the above parenting peace calm
conversations the connected family parenting
Harmony Beyond arguments a parents time to Lasting
connection with teens all right so as you can see
here what you're able to do is you're able to
take this idea and we were able to really dial
it in with language of what are those desires
and this is what makes it marketable when you
actually know how to communicate with somebody
exactly what those desires are and you're able
to package it in a way that is tied around what
are those needs what are those those things that
they need fulfilled now people want to actually
buy something like that from you okay now the
next thing that we want to do is we want to
put this together into an irresistible offer
an irresistible offer is something that people
just simply can't say no to you're able to tap
into those deepest desires that somebody has those
those those reasons why they want to take action
and what it is is you get them to feel what the
transformation is like on the other side of it
and this is one of the things that I work with
my clients with in my client growth accelerator
program is putting that irresistible offer
together how do we package it in a way now how
do we sell it in a way that actually is going to
make the kind of money that you want to make and
here's how we want to do this as we want to create
something that's going to attract these parents
to us like a training an ebook a webinar something
like that that's going to grow your email list you
want to provide content to people that's going to
provide value and transformation in people's lives
and what that does is that's going to draw those
people to you and then what you're able to do is
you're able to build trust with those people for
the end outcome that you're promising the ultimate
outcome of having stress-free communication
having that resilient relationship raising
those confident teenagers and being a powerful
parent in an environment that's normally chaos
and and and that speaks to any parent that
has teenagers right there because that's the
end transformation end result that they want and
if they've tried everything if they struggled if
they've gone through this they will be willing
to invest with you to take it to the next level
now where this goes Advanced is this is watch
this I want you to then brainstorm a track of
training that is level two through five of after
they go through this what could we upsell them to
and here's why we say this is because to build
a business that's marketable that goes and this
is what my clients who have worked with me for
years they say they wish they knew ahead of time
is that if you can look and think big picture
about where do you want to take somebody Beyond
just an initial training okay deepening the bond
and building trust strengthening trust advanced
communication mindful leadership leading your
parents guiding them towards self-confidence and
accountability a unified family emotional health
preparing them for Independence and lifelong
resilience and so what it is is that as you build
all of this build all of these pieces of level 1
through five together into one main program that
provides this big trans transformation and life
is what you're able to do is you're able to talk
big picture and it's all about being a connected
family blueprint and so for instance let's say
that somebody started they want to coach around
mindful parenting for teens but the truth is where
they're really going to make the most amount of
money is building a system to provide a blueprint
for families to go from conflict to confidence to
connection you could provide relationship coaching
for the parent uh counseling uh you could provide
um help for the parents communicate you could
provide it for raising the teens you can provide
it for helping raise different age groups about
helping them go on into their life after being
in the home and what ends up happening is is
that this creates a connection you can have
monthly coaching calls you can have a community of
people you can provide lifetime access to training
assessments and all of this and now this creates a
support system and and accountability that creates
the life that these families have always dreamed
of and people will make an investment in that they
might not invest just for communicating with their
teens but they will make an investment to want to
take their entire family to the next level and
that's what makes it marketable and we can when
you can think bigger picture at all of this I
want to start small and then I want to expand
out bigger picture now that becomes marketable
for us to reach the kind of people that we want
to reach in our business now listen if you're
a coach if you're a course creator if you're
somebody that wants some help putting all this
together that's what my client grth accelerator
is for and I'd love to help you be able to do that
we walk you through the whole process of choosing
your Niche dialing in your messaging figuring out
how do you promote this and reach the right people
how do we sell this to people so that you have
consistent income so that you can have massive
impact in your life and so that you have Clarity
on your messaging how to say it what to say what
are those words that gets people to take action
to buy from you and what this ultimately does
is this creates six and seven figure Financial
Freedom for you and ultimately time Freedom so
you're not having to work hundreds of hours
a week so that you can actually work just 5
to 10 hours a week like like I've been able to
do the last couple of years and build a seven
and even eight figure business and that's what I
do with people I help them go from zero starting
out to producing the life that they have always
wanted in their business and so I'd love to work
with you in my client growth accelerator
program make sure you get on the waiting
list make sure you check out some of the free
training some of the free classes that we have
in the description below I'll talk with you soon
have a good one let's get some results for you